1.  Before  doing  any other investigation, list two or three questions that this infographic 
and explanation  of methodology raise in your mind. 

question 1:
How did they actually define and measure  regional interest fo each state?

Google trends give relative search results which is a 0 - 100 scale as said by their trends
description, never giving absolute numbers. that makes me wonder if they just took the highest
single food per state, or did they normalize everything so one state’s huge population doesn’t dominate everything.

Does a high search interest really correlate to or equal "break up food"?
People search for all kinds of food for all kinds of reasons, what in is this data is leading me to believe that it has any relation to break up foods. Why should I believe it has anything to do with break up food simply based on time and regions? Also why are we only using those three specific data sources?

2. Where can you find Google Trends search data? Provide the URL.

You can find google search trend data on their official google trend website here:

https://trends.google.com/trends/

you can also use there explore webpage as well.

3.  The article concluded that “milkshakes take the crown as the ultimate breakup food, 
topping the list in six states.” Pull up Google Trends data on Milkshake (beverage) and 
change the date range to February 1,  2024 through February 28, 2025.

a) What is the highest peak recorded in the line chart for “Interest over time”?
The csv sheet shows highest peak at August 1st of 2024 at 100
b) What is the lowest dip recorded?
After downloading the csv it tells me that 12/1/2024 is the lowest dip at 70

4. At the top next to the box for “Milkshake,” there is a plus sign to add another search term. Click the plus sign to add a search for Hamburger (Food).

a) What is the highest peak recorded for searches using Hamburger?
The highest peak was recorded at 5/1/2024
 What is the lowest dip? 
The lowest dip was 12/1/2024

b) What happened to the line for Milkshake?
The line for milkshake was pushed to the bottom and turned blue.

What do the high and low look like now? 

The high for both looks smaller to fit the chart but the highs looks smaller in comparison to the search for hamburger vs milkshake

5. Why did the line for Milkshake change? Hint: Click on the icon next to “Interest over time” for more information about how trend results are displayed. 
Because the search interest over a specific time is displayed on a relative scale from 0 – 100, where 100 is the peak interest for that specific time of the chart, a value of 50 is an indication of half of the popularity while a 0 indicates insufficient data.

6. Add a third term to your search, this time for Breakup (Topic). 
a) Do you see any patterns that suggest a relationship between searches for Breakup and Hamburger? 
P don’t see any relation between breakups and hamburgers, the data pattern stays constant for hamburgers in relation to break ups, as breaks ups stayed at a constant 17 for 5 months, you can see the monthly hamburger data rises and falls in an even distribution per month.

b) How about between Breakup and Milkshake? 
You can clearly see a trend of milkshakes rising as breakups rise even if one or two months show a slight decrease the majority of the breakups correlated to milkshakes shows a rise in milkshake searches in correlation to breakups

7. What does all of this suggest about the reliability of the conclusions reached in the article? 
Reliability isn’t based on one single factor, it requires multiple relative searches along side multiple sources to match and confirm any speculation in patterns.
8. At the upper right of Google Trends, click on the link for “Back to Classic Explore.” Notice that this view includes a section for “Compared breakdown by subregion.” 
a) What was the top state by interest for Milkshake? 
Maryland
b) What was the top state by interest for Hamburger?
Alabama
9. Use the download icon to download a csv file with these search trend results. Save it to your DataAnalytics/week-01 folder as GTrends_milkshake_hamburger_2024.csv
